Finding Aid for the Arai Family Papers LSC.1254
UCLA Library Special Collections
Arai Family papers
1877-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
Arai family
LSC.1254
34.5 linear feet (69 boxes and 6 oversize boxes)
Ryichir Arai was born in 1855 and came to New York in 1876 to start the direct export of silk. Ryichir Arai, Toyo Morimura, and Morimoto Sato were founders of Japanese American Trade, and they promoted closer relations between Japan and the United States. Yoneo Arai, son of Ryichir Arai, has served as Resident Representative of The Tokio Marine & Fire Insurance Company, Ltd. United States Fire Branch, a director of Japan Society, Vice president of the Japan Society, and Chairman of the Board, Yamaichi Securities Company of New York., Inc. The collection consists of personal and business papers of Ryichir Arai and his son, Yoneo Arai. They also include Arai family photographs. Portions of this collection are in Japanese.
Conditions Governing Access
Portions of collection unprocessed. Material in Series 27 is unavailable for access. Please contact Special Collections reference (spec-coll@library.ucla.edu) for more information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Yoneo Arai, 1979.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 994622083606533
Biography
Ryichir Arai was born in 1855 in Japan; he came to the United States in 1876 and settled in New York City as a founder of the silk export trade between the United States and Japan; his son, Yoneo Arai, graduated from Harvard in 1912 and was a banker; Yoneo Arai served as resident representative of the Tokio Marine & Fire Insurance Company, Ltd. United States Fire Branch, vice president of the Japan Society, and Chairman of the Board, Yamaichi Securities Company of New York, Inc.
Additional Biographical Narrative
Ryichir Arai was born in 1855 and came to New York in 1876 to start the direct export of silk. Ryichir Arai, Toyo Morimura, and Morimoto Sato were founders of Japanese American Trade, and they promoted closer relations between Japan and the United States. Yoneo Arai, son of Ryichir Arai, has served as Resident Representative of The Tokio Marine & Fire Insurance Company, Ltd. United States Fire Branch, a director of Japan Society, Vice president of the Japan Society, and Chairman of the Board, Yamaichi Securities Company of New York., Inc. The papers include Yoneo Arai's business letters, stock inventory, financial records, and personal letters to his family and friends. Also included are Arai family photographs.
by Michiko Yoneda, June 1980
Scope and Content
Collection consists of personal and business papers of Ryichir Arai and his son, Yoneo Arai. Ryichir Arai's correspondence between 1876 and 1881 relates to his work as a founder of the silk export trade between the United States and Japan. His personal letters to his brother and adoptive father span the years 1881-95. The collection also includes Yoneo Arai's business correspondence, stock inventory, financial records, and personal correspondence to family and friends. 7 boxes contain photographs, and additional photos are dispersed throughout the collection. Photographs include family portraits, panoramic photos of Japan (1870s-1880s), and photos of various civic events and organizations.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Files
Series 2: Photographs
Series 3: Diaries, 1876-1910
Series 4: Biographic Data I - Includes Yoneo Arai
Series 5: Biographic Data II
Series 6: Ryichir's Letters in Tokyo to Brother
Series 7: Copybooks - Ryichir on His Japan Trips
Series 8: Letters to Ryichir Arai from Friends,, ca. 1900-10
Series 9: Ryichir Arai to Relatives & Friends after Arrival in New York, 1876
Series 10: Letters to Ryichir Arai from His Family
Series 11: Letters of Ryichir Arai, 1876-81, re Satogumi Business Matters
Series 12: Notes, Memoranda, Miscellaneous Mostly Undated
Series 13: Doshin Company Records
Series 14: Yokohama Kiito Co. Financial Records & Papers
Series 15: Yokohama Kiito Legal Papers
Series 16: Ryichir Arai's Letters re Job as Office Manager of Doshin Silk Trading Co.
Series 17: Investment Company Reports
Series 18: Original Letters
Series 19: T. Scott Miyakawa re Arai Papers
Series 20: Unidentified
Series 21: Envelopes
Series 22: Bound Journals
Series 23: Ledger
Series 24: Morimura Brothers
Series 25: Ryichir Arai
Series 26: Mr. and Mrs. Murai [Neighbors of Ryichir Arai]
Series 27: Unprocessed Materials
Related Material
Japanese American Research Project Collection of Material about Japanese in the United States (Collection 2010). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Japanese American Research Project - Fading Footsteps of the Issei (Collection 2010). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Arai Family Papers (24 items).
Business records.; Family papers.; Silk industry -- United States.; Japanese American families -- New York (State) -- New York -- Archives.; Bankers -- New York (State) -- New York -- Archives.; Businessmen -- New York (State) -- New York -- Archives.; Photographs.; Arai family--Archives.; Arai, Ryoichiro; Arai, Yoneo
- Files (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12, Box 13, Box 14, Box 15, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39, Box 40, Box 41, Box 42, Box 43, Box 44, Box 45, Box 46, Box 47, Box 48, Box 49, Box 50, Box 51, Box 52, Box 53, Box 54, Box 55, Box 56, Box 57, Box 58, Box 59, Box 60, Box 61, Box 62, Box 63, Box 64, Box 65, Box 66, Box 67, Box 68, Box 69)
  - Correspondence - Friends, 1969. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1969. (Box 1)
  - Retired persons, 1969. (Box 1)
  - Retirement projects, 1968-69. (Box 1)
  - MA [Mitsu Arai] file, 1969. (Box 1)
  - Bridge, 1971. (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1969. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Family, 1969. (Box 1)
  - Merrill Lynch, 1971. (Box 1)
  - Bills paid, 1971. (Box 1)
  - Insurance (health). (Box 1)
  - Merrill Lynch Pierce. (Box 1)
  - Fenner & Smith, 1970. (Box 1)
  - 600 Summer St. Stanford. (Box 1)
  - Insurance-Mony. (Box 1)
  - Equit & Much. (Box 1)
  - Putnam Trust, 1970. (Box 1)
  - Yamaichi Securities Company, Ltd., 1970 & 1971. (Box 2)
  - GPU (General Public Utilities) important correspondence, 1969-72. (Box 2)
  - Bills paid, 1972. (Box 2)
  - Yamaichi-Japan Account, 1970. (Box 2)
  - Connecticut & California Laws - Bank sets. (Box 2)
  - Federal Estate & Gift Taxes, 1971. (Box 2)
  - Yamaichi, 1962. (Box 2)
  - Yamaichi-Japan Yen account & Miscellaneous personal, 1970. (Box 2)
  - Yamaichi-New York, 1970. (Box 2)
  - Yoneo Arai & MA [Mitsu Arai] current financial positions, 1966-69. (Box 2)
  - Financial, October 1957 - January 1958. (Box 2)
  - MA [Mitsu Arai] & Yoneo Arai investments, 1951-56. (Box 2)
  - Putnam Trust Yoneo Arai Trustee account, 1970. (Box 2)
  - Putnam Trust & Merrill Lynch MA [Mitsu Arai] Trustee, 1970. (Box 3)
  - Personal - Financial general, 1956. (Box 3)
  - Bills paid, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Bills payable, 1949. (Box 3)
  - Bills paid, 1954. (Box 3)
  - Financial, 1955. (Box 3)
  - Financial, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Yoneo Arai Personal - Financial, 1953-55. (Box 3)
  - Financial, 1956. (Box 3)
  - Yoneo Arai Business - Personal, 1955-56. (Box 3)
  - Bills paid, 1970. (Box 3)
  - Financial, 1949-54. (Box 3)
  - Personal - Financial, 1947. (Box 3)
  - Financial - Miscellaneous, 1937. (Box 3)
  - Loomis MA [Mitsu Arai] Financial - Miscellaneous, 1939-40. (Box 3)
  - Financial - Miscellaneous, 1938. (Box 3)
  - Yoneo Arai & MA [Mitsu Arai] miscellaneous finance, 1935. (Box 3)
  - Ring binder of lecture notes for Salesman's class, (November 21, 1928-February 28, 1929). (Box 4)
  - MA [Mitsu Arai] special account Harris Upham & Strauss Bros., 1935. (Box 4)
  - Strauss Bros., 1937 & 1938. (Box 4)
  - MA [Mitsu Arai] special account, 1936 & 1937. (Box 4)
  - Ads & circulars (Yamaichi) stock journal, 1961. (Box 4)
  - Harris Upham, 1938 & 1959-61. (Box 4)
  - Irving Trust, 1937 & 1938. (Box 4)
  - Merrill Lynch, 1960 & 1961. (Box 4)
  - Brokers & Bank account. (Box 4)
  - Putnam Trust, 1959 & 1960. (Box 4)
  - Merrill Lynch, 1952-59. (Box 5)
  - Harris Upham, 1952 & 1954-58. (Box 5)
  - Putnam Trust, 1953, 1957 & 1958. (Box 5)
  - Fiduciary Trust, 1952-57. (Box 5)
  - Fiduciary Trust, 1950 & 1951. (Box 6)
  - Merrill Lynch, 1949-51. (Box 6)
  - Harris Upham: (Ryichir Arai), (MA [Mitsu Arai] & Yoneo Arai), (MA [Mitsu Arai]), 1950 & 1951 1940-49 1939 (Box 6)
  - Strauss Bros.: (MA [Mitsu Arai] & Ryichir Arai), (TA), 1941 1939 & 1940 (Box 6)
  - Irving Trust, (MA [Mitsu Arai]), 1939 (Box 6)
  - Starkweather & Company, (MA [Mitsu Arai] & Yoneo Arai), 1949 (Box 6)
  - Putnam Trust, (Yoneo Arai), 1947, 1948 1949. (Box 6)
  - Strauss Bros., (MA [Mitsu Arai]), 1939 (Box 7)
  - Harris Upham, (Ryichir Arai), 1942-48 (Box 7)
  - Pearl & Company, (MA [Mitsu Arai] spl), 1934 (Box 7)
  - Found loose: Tokyo Hilton, maps of Japan, articles, art book, Tokyo Olympics, (1964). (Box 7)
  - Japanese culture - Kyoto, Nagoya, tour guides, flower arrangement book, Garden club, art book, postcards (Box 8)
  - Japan tour, Certificate, pictures, understanding Japan. (Box 9)
  - Bank of Tokio Trust Co. (Box 10)
    - Financial statements bylaw, 1955-56.
    - Correspondence, 1955-56.
    - Minutes of meetings, 1955-66.
  - Banks - Japan, 1969-70. (Box 11)
  - Bank of Tokio - Personal, 1969. (Box 11)
  - Examination of the Bank of Tokio Trust & Company, 1958-59, 1961, 1966 & 1971. (Box 11)
  - Bank of Tokio Trust Company, 1971 & 1972. (Box 11)
  - Securities, 1950. (Box 11)
  - Financial, 1950. (Box 11)
  - Uji Movie Film Company, 1948-50. (Box 11)
  - Personal, 1950. (Box 11)
  - Personal - General, 1950. (Box 12)
  - Personal, 1948-49. (Box 12)
  - Fish Oil, 1949. (Box 12)
  - Insurance data, 1949. (Box 12)
  - Glen Avon Home, 1947-48. (Box 12)
  - Glen Avon Drive Building, 1947-48. (Box 12)
  - Personal, 1946 & 1947. (Box 12)
  - Glen Avon Drive Home plan, 1947. (Box 12)
  - Personal letters, 1940-45. (Box 13)
  - General Investment Company, 1941. (Box 13)
  - Personal letters, 1934-39. (Box 14)
  - Investment counsel, 1932-33. (Box 14)
  - Personal - Financial, 1937. (Box 14)
  - Seiichiro Iwasaki, 1929-31, 1933-35, 1938 & 1949. (Box 15)
  - Kashiwagi account, 1929-31. (Box 15)
  - Kashiwagi, 1938. (Box 15)
  - Kashiwagi & Iwasaki, 1941-44. (Box 15)
  - Yoneo Arai 80th Birthday, (August 26, 1969). (Box 15)
  - Yoneo Arai re decoration, 1969. (Box 15)
  - Yoneo Arai & MA [Mitsu Arai] estate planning, 1969. (Box 15)
  - Yoneo Arai miscellaneous, 1965. (Box 15)
  - Medical, 1964. (Box 15)
  - Yoneo Arai Medicare, 1970. (Box 15)
  - Accidents, 1970. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - Family, 1971. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - MA [Mitsu Arai], 1971. (Box 15)
  - Residence plans, 1964. (Box 16)
  - Personal, 1965. (Box 16)
  - World Trip, 1965 (Box 16)
  - Letters awaiting reply, 1964. (Box 16)
  - Bills paid, 1965. (Box 16)
  - Morimura Employee Funds, 1965. (Box 16)
  - Gunma Bank. (Box 16)
  - Harris Upham, 1966. (Box 16)
  - Bank of Trust Company, 1967. (Box 16)
  - Merrill Lynch, 1966. (Box 16)
  - Putnam Trust Company, 1965-66. (Box 16)
  - Yamaichi Yoneo Arai Investment correspondence, 1965-66. (Box 16)
  - Mitsui Bank, 1966. (Box 16)
  - Japanese society, 1962, 1963. (Box 16)
  - Clippings, 1965-66. (Box 16)
  - Financial - General, 1963. (Box 17)
  - Yamaichi, 1954. (Box 17)
  - Tokyo Marine, 1961-64. (Box 17)
  - Personal Arai Family, 1966. (Box 17)
  - Japan Society, 1962. (Box 17)
  - Home maintenance. (Box 17)
  - Articles, 1963-64. (Box 18)
  - Personal - Miscellaneous, 1963-64. (Box 18)
  - Kashiwagi, 1933-34 & 1937. (Box 18)
  - Yoneo Arai Will revised, 1964. (Box 18)
  - Congressional record (Masaoka - Ishikawa). (Box 18)
  - Finance, 1964. (Box 18)
  - Tailors tack master. (Box 18)
  - Hilton, 1963-64. (Box 18)
  - Selected file re Hilton, 1956-57. (Box 18)
  - Imperial Hotel - Hilton, 1954. (Box 18)
  - Letters to Giro Koike, 1956-57. (Box 19)
  - Yamaichi Hilton, 1956-61. (Box 19)
  - Hilton financing, 1954-58. (Box 19)
  - Clippings, 1964. (Box 19)
  - Old Wills. (Box 19)
  - Retirement home. (Box 19)
  - Japan Society Fund Raising Campaign, 1966-67. (Box 19)
  - Japan Society, 1967-68. (Box 19)
  - Japan Society Fund, 1969. (Box 19)
  - Dextor French, August 1964-January 1965. (Box 19)
  - Japan Society - re building & fund raising data, 1968. (Box 20)
  - House, 1962-64. (Box 20)
  - Bank of Tokyo. (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 20)
  - Japan Society. (Box 21)
  - Inf. Stock investment (Yamaichi). (Box 21)
  - Articles. (Box 21)
  - Letters (awaiting reply). (Box 21)
  - Ads & Circulars (electric) Japan utility company reports, 1962. (Box 21)
  - Letters. (Box 22)
  - Bills. (Box 22)
  - General, 1964-65. (Box 22)
  - Clippings, 1962. (Box 22)
  - World Trip, 1963 (Box 22)
  - South Pacific travel data, 1961. (Box 23)
  - General. (Box 23)
  - Travel data, 1960. (Box 23)
  - Yoneo Arai, 1945. (Box 23)
  - Japan trip, 1961. (Box 23)
  - Kosaka, 1962-63. (Box 23)
  - In Japan - General, 1961. (Box 23)
  - Personal, 1964. (Box 23)
  - N.H. students & teacher - Yale, 1943-46. (Box 23)
  - Packages to Japan, 1946-48. (Box 23)
  - General - Miscellaneous, 1956. (Box 23)
  - World Tour, 1957-58. (Box 23)
  - Retired Men's Association, 1967. (Box 23)
  - Personal, 1956. (Box 23)
  - Health Insurance, 1958. (Box 23)
  - Letters - awaiting reply, 1968. (Box 23)
  - Personal correspondnece - Family & relatives, 1968. (Box 23)
  - Correspondence. (Box 24)
    - Family re Pete, 1962-68.
    - Friends, 1967-68.
    - MA [Mitsu Arai], 1968.
    - Miscellaneous & reports, 1968.
  - Retired Men's Association, 1967-68. (Box 24)
  - St. George's School, 1966-68. (Box 24)
  - Japan trip - Miscellaneous, 1967. (Box 24)
  - Letters - Japan trip, 1967. (Box 24)
  - Japan, 1967. (Box 24)
  - General, 1967. (Box 24)
  - Articles - Miscellaneous, 1959. (Box 24)
  - Clippings - Memos, etc., 1966-67. (Box 24)
  - Articles - Medical, 1962-63. (Box 24)
  - Correspondence & memos, 1967. (Box 24)
    - Family Ryo, Louise grandchildren.
    - Miscellaneous.
    - Friends.
    - Relatives.
  - Travel Expo, '67. (Box 24)
  - Harvard 1912 Reunion. (Box 24)
  - Personal correspondence, 1951-52, 1966 & 1970. (Box 25)
  - Harvard 1912 60th Reunion. (Box 25)
  - Travel, 1965 & 1970. (Box 25)
  - Clippings, 1971. (Box 25)
  - Bills paid, 1960. (Box 25)
  - Fox club, 1972. (Box 25)
  - Fox club Drive, 1963. (Box 25)
  - Japan History Report, 1970. (Box 25)
  - Correspondence - Friends, 1970. (Box 25)
  - St. George's School Fund, 1962-64. (Box 26)
  - Financial, 1964. (Box 26)
  - Salary, 1962. (Box 26)
  - Harvard Reunion, 1962. (Box 26)
  - Yoneo Arai & MA [Mitsu Arai] re investment holding, 1957-60. (Box 26)
  - Yoneo Arai & MA [Mitsu Arai] Will, 1954, 1958 & 1959. (Box 26)
  - Harvard Yenching Institute. (Box 26)
  - High Fidelity, 1964. (Box 26)
  - Yamaichi, 1964-65. (Box 26)
  - Mitsui Bank, 1964-65. (Box 26)
  - Putnam Trust, 1965. (Box 26)
  - Merrill Lynch, 1965. (Box 26)
  - Yoneo Arai Personal, 1935-52. (Box 26)
  - American Express, 1965. (Box 26)
  - Japan Society, 1964. (Box 26)
  - Jenning file. (Box 26)
  - Banks of Tokyo, 1955-56. (Box 27)
  - Merrill Lynch, 1965. (Box 27)
  - Strauss Bros. bonds to Japan, 1941. (Box 27)
  - Inventory, 1941. (Box 27)
  - Utility Company, Assoc. Gas & Electric Company, 1936 1933-35). (Box 27)
  - Letters, 1952. (Box 27)
  - Building, 1951. (Box 27)
  - Taxation, Japan & the United States convention, 1957. (Box 27)
  - Record bank, stock. (Box 27)
  - Fox club, 1948. (Box 27)
  - Personal letters, 1935, 1948-49 & 1955-56. (Box 27)
  - General, 1958-60. (Box 28)
  - Personal foreign correspondence Yoneo Arai, 1954-58. (Box 28)
  - Yoneo Arai Personal - General, 1953-57. (Box 29)
  - Yoneo Arai Personal - General, 1947-53. (Box 30)
  - Standard Survey & Casualty Company, 1934-35 & 1940. (Box 31)
  - Estate of Kenkichi Kagami. (Box 31)
  - Marine Branch Data (Tokio Marine & Fire Insurance Company), 1930-33 & 1941 (Box 31)
  - Maynard Report on Prod. Policy. (Box 31)
  - Fire branch (Tokio Marine & Fire Insurance Co.), 1935 (Box 32)
  - Income tax, 1931-37. (Box 32)
  - MM custody. (Box 32)
  - Irving Trust Company, 1936. (Box 32)
  - Old Trust receipt Irving Trust Co. (Box 33)
  - Banks Trust Co. (Box 33)
  - Public National Bank. (Box 33)
  - Pearl C.K.P. Ryichir Arai special account, 1932-33. (Box 33)
  - Coombe, Kerr & Pratt. (Box 33)
  - Bought, Sold. (Box 33)
  - Miyo, 1928-36. (Box 33)
  - MM's income tax, 1934. (Box 33)
  - Irving Trust Co. rationing, 1933 (Box 33)
  - C.K.P., 1931-32. (Box 34)
  - Financial - Miscellaneous Ryichir Arai, 1935. (Box 34)
  - Strauss Bros., 1937. (Box 34)
  - Harris Upham & Co. paper, 1936. (Box 34)
  - Irving Trust Co. Harris Upham Report of Security, 1937 & 1938. (Box 34)
  - Letters to Japan, 1934 & 1936. (Box 34)
  - Letters from Japan, 1934-36. (Box 34)
  - United States letters, 1934-36. (Box 34)
  - Tokio Marine & Fire Insurance Co. investment data, 1934. (Box 34)
  - Reports on Cotton & Marine Bus. (Box 35)
  - A & C investment data, 1939. (Box 35)
  - Marine & Cotton, 1935 & 1939. (Box 35)
  - Fire Co. (Box 35)
  - Financial plan, 1940. (Box 35)
  - Finance Branch office, 1940. (Box 35)
  - Two Standards Sale, 1940. (Box 35)
  - Data from Japan, 1939. (Box 35)
  - United States letters, 1941. (Box 35)
  - Canadian Branches, 1941. (Box 35)
  - Two Standards Sale, 1941. (Box 35)
  - Tokio Marine & Fire Insurance Company, Inland Marine Insurance - Mizusawa, Robert. (Box 36)
  - Letters from Japan, 1941. (Box 36)
  - Letters to Japan, 1941. (Box 36)
  - Investment in Japan - Mitsubishi, 1954-58. (Box 36)
  - Japanese stocks, Japan Investment (Mitsubishi Trust Co.), 1951-53. (Box 37)
  - Japanese bond, 1940-59 (Box 37)
  - Personal - Financial re money bonds, 1956. (Box 38)
  - Re Japan Investment, 1941-46. (Box 38)
  - Morimura Bros. Benefit Fund, 1944-47. (Box 38)
  - Toyo Spinning Co. (Textile industry). (Box 39)
  - Tokio Marine & Fire Insurance. (Box 39)
  - Personal records, (1904). (Box 39)
  - Checks (Irving Trust Co.), 1930-36. (Box 40)
  - Scott Miyakawa - A History of the East Coast Japanese Americans, 1970. (Box 41)
  - General, 1970-72. (Box 41)
  - Walnau Creek, 1972. (Box 41)
  - Correspondence - Family & friends, 1971. (Box 41)
  - Banks - Brokers - Yoneo Arai & MA [Mitsu Arai] financial & medical. (Box 41)
  - Medical, 1968-71. (Box 41)
  - Correspondence - Family & friends, 1972. (Box 42)
  - Clippings, 1972. (Box 42)
  - Putnam Trust Company, 1972. (Box 42)
  - Family letters. (Box 42)
  - Business letters. (Box 43)
  - Morimura, Arai & Co. (Box 43)
  - Documents, 1924 (Box 43)
  - Family correspondence, 1964 (Box 43)
  - Cards. (Box 44)
  - Important references. (Box 44)
  - Yokohama Ki-ito Kabushiki Kaisha. (Box 44)
  - Morimura, Arai & Co. (Box 44)
  - Morimura Trust Fund (Bank of Tokyo). (Box 44)
  - Magazine clippings, 1956-57. (Box 44)
  - Real estate. (Box 44)
  - Ryo, 1964-65. (Box 44)
  - Photographs (more detailed item description in Photographs section). (Box 45, Box 46, Box 47)
  - Checks. (Box 48)
  - Letters to Mr. Yoneo Arai, 1908; (4 folders). (Box 48)
  - Checks. (Box 49)
  - Letters., (5 folders). (Box 49)
  - Letters, 1908. (Box 50)
  - School papers - Geography, American History. (Box 50)
  - Business financial statements, 1903. (Box 50)
  - Painting on rice paper, Toy - top. (Box 50)
  - Name cards (business). (Box 51)
  - Photographs - friends. (Box 51)
  - Business letters, July 1924-January 1925 & December 1927-May 1928 (Box 52)
  - Y.K.K. Silk Deptartment closing account report, August 23, 1924-November 2, 1927 (Box 52)
  - Letters to Y.S. Bank. (Box 52)
  - Morimura, Arai & Co., May 6, 1913-March 7, 1917 (Box 52)
  - Article - Yoneo Arai. (Box 52)
  - Clippings, January 1-November 17, 1923 (Box 52)
  - I) Silk market, II) Statistic resource. (Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 52)
  - FY Kitzmiller Sons Co. bankruptcy proceedings, in debt to Morimura, Arai & Company, 1923. (Box 53)
  - FY Kitzmiller Sons Co. B.H.A. Hofmann's memos, 1928-30. (Box 53)
  - Phoenix Silk Manufacturing Company Inc. (same as Paterson Silk Textile Institute) correspondence, Notary public Dissolution of the firm of Morimura, Arai & Co., 1927-38. January 16, 1925. (Box 53)
    - * 4 Postcards bids and offers for stocks and bonds in Phoenix Silk Manufacturing Co., 2 × 4.
  - FY Kitzmiller Sons Company financial papers. (Box 53)
  - FY Kitzmiller Sons Co. correspondence, 1926-29. (Box 53)
  - FY Kitzmiller Sons Co. credit memo, 1925-29. (Box 53)
  - FY Kitzmiller Sons Co. correspondence, 1930-37. (Box 53)
  - Investment rice farm in Texas, Report to Mr. Arai and Associates evaluating R. Onishi's bookkeeping and suggesting new methods, by unknown person (prob and accountant), June 11, 1909.; 11pp. Typed. (Box 53)
  - Imperial Brush Co. (Osaka Seigyo Kaisha). (Box 53)
  - Imperial Brush Company correspondence, 1902 & 1905. (Box 53)
  - Osaka Seigyo Kaisha agreement, 1895. (Box 53)
  - Imperial Brush Co. agreement between Ryichir Arai and Richard Von Briessen of New York City firm of Arai and Briessen, and J. Funnell Christian of London, England, April 1912. (Box 53)
  - Frank F. Pels Company, Inc. correspondence re mortgage interest, memos, financial statements, 1930-38. (Box 53)
  - Frank F. Pels Company, Inc. credit memo, 1927-28. (Box 53)
  - Frank F. Pels Company, Inc. Hofmann's memo, 1930-32. (Box 53)
  - Frank F. Pels Company, Inc. financial statements, 1931-37. (Box 53)
  - Paterson Silk Textile Institute (same as Phoenix Silk Manufacturing Company Inc.) Certificate of Incorporation, (Arai Ryichir, Incorporator), 1902 (Box 53)
  - Pennsylvania Textile Company, reports to creditors, B.H.A. Hofmann (Arai's broker, accountant?), 1926-35 (Box 53)
  - Phoenix Silk Manufacturing Company, Inc. (Box 54)
    - Credit memos, 1928 & 1934.
    - B.H.A. Hofmann's memo, 1927-36.
    - Bankruptcy proceeding.
    - Credit memo, 1926-27.
    - Agreements, 1925-31.
  - Putney, Twombly & Hall Attorneys at Law. (Box 54)
  - Rossville Silk Mills, 1924-30. (Box 54)
  - Nathan & Louis Taback vs. Morimura, Arai & Co. (Box 54)
  - Ellsworth L. Williams, 1926-29. (Box 54)
  - Companies in which Arai Ryichir was interested or involved, 1917. (Box 54)
  - Arai Ryichir financial statement, August 1926 (Box 54)
  - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 54)
  - Sendai Hagi The Industrial Transition in Japan, undated (Box 54)
  - Reference material. (Box 54)
  - Statistics, 1924. (Box 54)
  - Financial records & statements (Phoenix Silk Manufacturing Co.), 1926-34. (Box 54)
  - Hoshino family tree & history. (Box 55)
  - Published materials on the Hoshino & Arai families. (Box 55)
  - Correspondence. (Box 55)
    - Relatives. (Box 55)
    - Otake Shoji, 1908-09. (Box 55)
    - Arai Yoneo, 1917. (Box 55)
    - Morimura Ichizaemon. (Box 55)
    - Morimura Yasue. (Box 55)
    - Murai Yasutaka. (Box 55)
    - Kakiage Junshiro, 1904-11. (Box 55)
    - Morimura Kaisaku, (1895, 1910, 1911 & 1914). (Box 55)
    - Personal, addressed Arai Ryichir. (Box 55)
    - Kiku Arai, 1895. (Box 55)
    - Arai Ryichir, 1915-17. (Box 55)
    - Shibusawa Eiichi. (Box 55)
    - Matsukata Shokuma. (Box 55)
    - Unidentified. (Box 55)
  - Private Investigaton's report re Matsukata Family, 1911. (Box 55)
  - Miyo Arai personal papers. (Box 55)
    - 3 Report cards from Ingleside School, May-December 1910.; (5 × 8).
    - Health/physical condition card, October-May 1910.; (3 × 7).
  - Arai Ryichir. (Box 55)
    - Personal History. (Box 55)